<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-19T14:59:17-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Introduction to Markov Chains</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/22/Markov-Chains.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction to Markov Chains" /><published>2020-08-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/22/Markov-Chains</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/22/Markov-Chains.html">&lt;p&gt;Markov chains are fairly simple to understand and the concept is easy to understand. They’re used in many different applicaitons such as in finance, statistical modeling, and queueing theory. A famous examnples is in its implemenation in Google’s page ranking algorithm, PageRank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a scenario, outside there are only two different temperatures, hot and cold. You want to be able to predict the temperature outside. What we may know is that if one day is cold, it relates to what tomorrow’s temperature will be. This is esestially what a Markov Chain attempts to capture. The probablility of staying in the same state and transitioning to the next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s add more information. We observe that there’s a 60% chance of it staying cold and a 50% chance of it staying hot. We can then get the tranisiton probablilites by subtracting one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog-images/Markov-Chain-Example.png&quot; alt=&quot;Markov Chain Example&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog-images/Markov-Chain-Example.png&quot; width=&quot;50&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Markov chains are fairly simple to understand and the concept is easy to understand. They’re used in many different applicaitons such as in finance, statistical modeling, and queueing theory. A famous examnples is in its implemenation in Google’s page ranking algorithm, PageRank. Here is a scenario, outside there are only two different temperatures, hot and cold. You want to be able to predict the temperature outside. What we may know is that if one day is cold, it relates to what tomorrow’s temperature will be. This is esestially what a Markov Chain attempts to capture. The probablility of staying in the same state and transitioning to the next. Let’s add more information. We observe that there’s a 60% chance of it staying cold and a 50% chance of it staying hot. We can then get the tranisiton probablilites by subtracting one.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kiwifruit</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/08/22/kiwifruit.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kiwifruit" /><published>2018-08-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-08-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/08/22/kiwifruit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/08/22/kiwifruit.html">&lt;p&gt;Kiwifruit (often abbreviated as kiwi), or Chinese gooseberry is the edible
berry of several species of woody vines in the genus Actinidia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most common cultivar group of kiwifruit is oval, about the size of a large
hen’s egg (5–8 cm (2.0–3.1 in) in length and 4.5–5.5 cm (1.8–2.2 in) in
diameter). It has a fibrous, dull greenish-brown skin and bright green or
golden flesh with rows of tiny, black, edible seeds. The fruit has a soft
texture, with a sweet and unique flavor.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>\[author\]</name></author><summary type="html">Kiwifruit (often abbreviated as kiwi), or Chinese gooseberry is the edible berry of several species of woody vines in the genus Actinidia.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Apples</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/08/21/apples.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apples" /><published>2018-08-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-08-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/08/21/apples</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/08/21/apples.html">&lt;p&gt;An apple is a sweet, edible fruit produced by an apple tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple trees are cultivated worldwide, and are the most widely grown species in
the genus Malus. The tree originated in Central Asia, where its wild ancestor,
Malus sieversii, is still found today. Apples have been grown for thousands of
years in Asia and Europe, and were brought to North America by European
colonists.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jill</name></author><summary type="html">An apple is a sweet, edible fruit produced by an apple tree.</summary></entry></feed>